字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
哥伦比亚电影公司
极限特工
他偷走晶片，躲进去了
He stole the chip, he's inside.
我看到他了
I see him.
阿奇！
Kirill!
该干活了
Time to work.
[国安局情报中心]
[维特山，维吉尼亚州]
零点三十分时，任务宣告失败
At 0030 hours, the mission deviated from the set parameters.
探员被杀并不在计划之内
It wasn't part of the plan for our agent to get shot in the back.
身分确认
Identity confirmed.
麦格遇害时传送了一些资料
McGrath was uploading some data to us when he was killed.
你看看，我不确定这是什么
Take a look at this. I'm not sure yet exactly what it is.
- 一个合成分子的部份  - 纪本
- A fragment of a complex molecule.  - Gibbons.
我们认为它跟前苏联生化武器…
We think it's a link to a Soviet bio-weapon...
“寂静之夜”有关
...called Silent Night.
- 詹姆士，他怎么来了？ - 我找他来的
- James, what the hell is he doing here?  - I called him in.
我们已损失三名探员，他帮得上忙
We've lost three agents already. You could use the help.
狙杀探员的是“无政府99”
I found out your agents were killed by this group, Anarchy 99.
他们原是军人，能轻易辨识出训练有素的探员
They're ex-military. They can smell the training on our agents a mile away.
我想我们该试试新方法了
Sir, I think it's time we tried something new.
这些不是我们的人，他们是谁？中情局的？
These guys aren't ours. Who are they? CIA?
是平民百姓，是罪犯、雇兵、杀手
No, civilians. Convicts, mercs, contract killers.
社会底层最机灵也最强的份子
The best and brightest of the bottom of the barrel.
- 他们根本是人渣  - 他们好用、能牺牲又肯出力
- They're the scum of the earth.  - Programmable, expendable, effective.
我想这是最好的办法
I think it's our best shot.
与其送羊入虎口
Do we want to drop another mouse in the snake pit?
还不如放只毒蛇去偷袭他们
Or send our own snake and let him crawl in?
[乡村俱乐部 非会员勿入]
[沙加缅度，加州]
[玩滑板是犯罪]
快点，小弟，真是的
Come on, Pepe. This is unbelievable.
喂！
Hello!
动作快点，听着
Well, it's about time. Now, listen....
你是哪里人？墨西哥？我没有恶意
Were you coming from Tijuana? I don't mean to be rude.
别停在太阳底下，烤漆会褪色
Keep it out of the sun. I don't want the paint to fade.
你听的懂英文吧？拿去，这够你花了
Do you understand English? I pay enough for you people.
来吧，珍娜，你会喜欢这里的
Come on, Janelle. You're gonna love this place.
- 迪克，你好  - 这是珍娜
- Dick, how are you?  - This is Janelle.
- 快报警  - 开我车的人是谁？
- Call 911 .  - Who's driving my car?
我是霍议员，加州州议员
Senator Hotchkiss! California state Senate!
听着，刚刚有人偷了我的车
Listen, somebody just stole my car!
红色敞篷车，立刻靠边停车
You, in the red Corvette! Pull over immediately!
是啊，条子追我，因为我偷了这车
Yeah, yeah. These monkeys are following me because I took this car.
这车不是我的，它太花俏了
Obviously the car doesn't belong to me, it's not my style.
它是迪克的车，霍迪克，加州州议员
It belongs to Dick, Dick Hotchkiss, a California state senator.
就是他提案禁止饶舌歌曲…
You remember Dick. He tried to ban rap music...
因为他觉得饶舌歌鼓吹暴力
...because he feels the lyrics promote violence.
那是音乐，迪克
It's music, Dick!
他也想提案禁止电玩…
He also wants to pull every video game off every shelf in the country...
因为他觉得电玩退化了下一代的智能
...because he feels that the video games diminish the intelligence of our youth.
拜托，迪克
Come on, Dick.
那是我们唯一的教育啊
It's the only education we got.
迪克，你是个坏蛋，我们对付坏蛋的方法
You're a bad man. You know what we do to bad men.
就是处罚
We punish them.
迪克，欢迎进入桑德特区
Dick, you've just entered the Xander zone.
我正带着一串条子往前冲
I'm coming in hot with a side of bacon!
快、快啊
Go, go, go!
快拉开
Pull it! Pull it!
好耶
Yes!
快去拿摄影机，快
Go get the cameras! Go! Go! Go!
教训你做人别太过份，迪克
Moral is, don't be a dick, Dick!
拿回摄影机了？好，走人
You guys got the cameras? All right, let's go, let's go!
再会啦
Peace out!
厉害
Outstanding.
谢了
Thank you.
- 你好  - 这些人是你请来的？
- What's up?  - You invited these people?
当然不是
Of course not.
好傢伙，你好啊
That's my dog! What's up?
今天真是太棒了，你真猛
Today was off the hook! You're psycho, bro!
猛？简直是帅呆了
Psycho? That was off the chain, man!
你有耍出那个超炫的动作吗？
Yo, yo, yo! What's up with that crazy trick that we've been hearing about?
- 蜘蛛人空中翻滚技？ - 当然
- My Superman seat-grab barrel roll?  - Word.
我还在练习
I'm still working on it.
你真难找
You're a hard guy to get ahold of.
你这种运动员该要有专属电玩游戏
You know, an athlete like you should really have his own video game.
金乔丹，我能帮你
Jordan King. I can make it happen.
- 我以后会再跟你联络  - 没问题
- I'll hold on to this for later.  - You do that.
他不会出卖自己的，他就是他
You know he'll never sell out. That's why he is who he is.
你别烦他了，是谁请你来的？
So you need to relax. Who invited you, anyway?
闭嘴
Shut up.
听着，我是说真的，我能拿到网路预售的预付款
Listen, this is for real. I can get us an advance on Internet pre-sales.
你只要去巴哥巴哥或哪里
So you need to just go to Pago Pago or something.
找女人，我无所谓，去渡个假
Get some girls, do them all. I don't care. Go on vacation.
是布拉布拉，这里的女人就够了
It's Bora Bora, J. I got enough girls here.
你何时开始这么爱钱的？
Since when did you care so much about money?
我只是要你先避避锋头
I just need you to lay low till the heat's off, okay?
我经营地下网站，我要卖录影带，但不要你坐牢
I run a secret website. I got tapes to make and I can't do that with you in jail.
- 你看过了吗？ - 我不管，听我的话
- Did you see that?  - I don't care. Listen to me.
我是无敌的
I'm untouchable.
趴下！进去！快点
Let's go! Get out! Move!
好啦，我音乐会关小声一点
Okay, I'll turn down the music.
不就一辆车而已吗？
It was only a Corvette.
快点，菜都快凉了
Let's go, baby. Your order is getting cold.
- 要来点咖啡吗？ - 给我来点炒马铃薯吧
- Want coffee?  - Can you give me some hash browns?
- 好  - 别炒过头了，我喜欢软一点
- Sure.  - Make them sloppy. I like them runny.
我怎么会在这里？
How did I get here?
两个大个子十分钟前丢下你，叫我好好照顾你
Two big guys dropped you off 10 minutes ago. Told me to look after you.
来点咖啡？你看来很需要
You look like you could use some coffee.
你没事吧？
You all right?
没事
Fine.
干嘛？你有问题吗？
I said, you got a problem, boy?
没，没问题
No. No problem.
- 大家不准动  - 不准动
- Nobody make a move!  - Nobody move!
想叫他去搬救兵？闭嘴
Just couldn't let him leave. Keep your goddamned mouth shut!
- 别乱动，不然你死定了  - 把钱全拿出来，快
- Keep still or you'll stop breathing.  - Empty the goddamn register!
退后
Get back!
退后、退后
Get back. Get back!
- 漂亮，大明星  - 你是谁？
- Well done, Mr. Cage.  - Who the hell are you?
纪本，奥纪本
The name's Gibbons. Augustus Gibbons.
你似乎很不爽，怎么了？
You seem upset. Is there a problem?
- 这是什么地方？ - 看起来是餐厅
- What is this place?  - Looks like a diner.
答的真好
That's clever.
你差一点就骗倒我了
You almost had me going there for a while.
一开始我有点头昏，后来我开始注意到一些事
I was a bit groggy before, then I started noticing things.
那里坐了个衣冠楚楚的分析师…
Like, you got a stockbroker over here, all dressed up...
看工商时报，在股市休市的星期天早上
...reading the Financial Times on Sunday when the market's closed.
不太合理，但我还可以接受
Unlikely, but okay, I can go with that.
我也能接受这个抢匪用警用的制式手枪
I could even go with the stick-up man packing a cop-issue Beretta.
知道最大的问题出在哪里吗？就是她
But you want to know where you blew it? With her.
我舅妈在餐厅工作了一辈子
My aunt was in the restaurant business.
专职女服务生绝不会穿高跟鞋
There's no way a career waitress comes to work in high heels.
那样她的脚铁定会长水泡
She'd have blisters the size of pancakes.
而如果她是假扮的，那这整个场景就是假的
And if she ain't real, then this whole thing ain't real.
所以我知道这场戏再怎么演…
That's how I knew that this bozo wouldn't get a shot off...
这笨蛋也绝不会开枪
...even if we waited till St. Patrick's Day.
因为枪里只有空包弹
Because there's nothing but blanks in these guns.
对了，我无意挑剔…
Oh, and no offense...
但他们的演技真是够烂
...but their performances were terrible.
很好，非常好
That's good. That's very good.
该你了，大帅哥
It's your turn, pretty boy.
- 这到底是怎么回事？ - 这是测验，你高分通过了
- What the hell is going on here?  - lt was a test that you aced.
- 他的态度不太好  - 什么？
- He seems to have a poor attitude.  - Excuse me?
- 要不要把他扔回去？ - 不，我喜欢他的态度
- Should we throw him back?  - Hell, no. I love his attitude.
进行下一步，快去联络
Let's take this to the next level. Get on the Sat-Com.
什么下一步？
Take what to the next level?
- 什么下一步？ - 全员十分钟内离去
- Yo! Take what?  - I want everybody out in 10 minutes.
我不奉陪
I don't play this game.
- 送麦克就医，否则他脸就毁了  - 我还要回派对去
- Get Mike a doctor or he'll look like me.  - I got a party.
- 让他闭嘴  - 别忘了赔我窗户的钱
- Shut him up.  - And pay for my windows!
怎么通过测验的老是些烂人？
Why is it always the assholes who pass the tests?
你们最近不会都到过餐厅吧？
You guys haven't been to any diners lately, huh?
餐厅胜出者
Diner finalists.
- 怎么，没咖啡啊？ - 好耶
- What, no coffee?  - Oh, yeah.
- 指挥军官在此  - 开始了
- Here comes the ROTC.  - Here we go.
- 我的花生米呢？ - 酷啊
- Where's my peanuts?  - Nice.
帮我叫空姐过来一下吧
Can you ask for the stewardess?
- 预备放减速伞  - 知道了，减速伞预备
- Standing by to deploy drogue.  - Roger, deploying drogue parachute.
- 这会很痛  - 这是在搞什么？
- This will hurt.  - What the hell?
- 放出减速伞  - 知道了
- Release drogue now.  - Roger.
这不好吧
This ain't right!
这算不了什么！
I live for this shit!
不赖嘛
Not bad!
再来一次吧
Let's do that again!
靠，这里是哥伦比亚
Holy shit. This is Colombia.
可卡因，这些都是可卡因树
Cocaine, man. These are coke plants!
没钥匙
No keys.
- 你在干嘛？ - 这些可值钱了
- What the hell are you doing?  - You know what this shit's worth?
怎么？测验人员来了？
What now? Is this another test?
- 我们过河去，快  - 是啊，快跑吧
- Let's go across the river. Let's go!  - Yeah, good idea! Good idea!
你们真是比我强太多了，我想我测验不及格了
You monkeys are too good for me. I failed this test.
你们有带喝的吗？
You guys got something to drink?
真高兴又见面了
Nice to see you again, fellas.
是啊
Yeah, you too.
他们这回可真是大费周章
Boy, they went all out on this one.
不会吧？
You've got to be kidding.
好了，笨蛋
Okay, funny guys.
见识一下我们怎么处置入侵者吧
I'll show you what we do when you get in our business.
绑住我们，逼我们听你讲话？
What? Hog-tie us and force us to listen to your bad accent?
不
No.
我们砍断他们的脚筋看着他们痛苦挣扎
We cut their Achilles tendon and watch them flop around like a marionette.
除非你有话跟我说重要的情报
Unless you have something to tell me, something I need to know?
好吧，你很矮
Okay. You're short.
我朋友说你可以去换个发型，放开我
My friend says you could use a haircut to update your style. Get off me.
闭嘴
Shut up!
你刚刚才叫我们讲话，现在却要闭嘴？
Two seconds ago you told us to talk. Now it's "Shut up?"
我无意挑剔，但你真不会逼供
I don't mean to nitpick, but you're the worst at this torture thing.
你再打我，我就扁死你
You slap me again, I'm going to throw you a beating.
希望你这样有领比较多酬劳
I hope they're paying you extra for this.
这样吧，也许我该先割了你的鼻子
You know what, funny guy? Maybe I'll cut off your nose first.
笨蛋
Funny guy.
怪了，这上面有真正的血腥味
What's funny is, this actually smells like real blood.
希望你喜欢，这会是你最后闻到的东西了
I hope you like it, because it's the last thing you're going to smell.
我中枪了
I'm hit! I'm hit! I'm hit!
维多，快帮忙
Virg! Give me a hand.
我们是哥伦比亚政府军
This is the Colombian army!
快投降，你们已被包围！
Give up, you're surrounded!
自己走，小杰
Try to walk, T.J. Try to walk.
维多，快走
Virg! Get out here!
去他的，人不为己天诛地灭
To hell with this. Every man for himself.
我去找交通工具
I'll get us some wheels.
在这等着
Hang in there.
祝好运
Good luck.
那个骑机车的就是毒枭！
The guy on the bike, that's the drug lord!
快逮住他！
Let's get him!
小杰
T.J.!
X，我在这里
X! I'm over here! X!
他在那里！
There he is!
我们把他烤焦了！
We toasted his ass!
我弄了一辆机车
I got us a bike.
胆小鬼！
Pussies!
看谁来了，科学怪人，打开我的手铐，我要扁死你
Look who it is. Frankenstein. Uncuff me so I can beat the shit out of you.
别激动，你刚以第一名毕业
Relax, X, you just graduated at the head of your class.
你在胡说什么？你差点害死我们
What are you talking about? You almost got us killed.
- 我们知道哥国军队正在逼近  - 什么？
- We knew the army was moving.  - Excuse me?
是我建议拿你当诱饵，怎样？
It was my idea to send you as a decoy. How do you like that?
- 你真是个身手矫健的老人  - 起来
- You're pretty fast for an old man.  - Get up.
陪我走一走
Walk with me.
我相信只要有好的环境，人是会改变的
I believe under the right circumstances, a man can change.
举例来说，昨晚你展现了勇气、领导能力…
For instance, last night you exhibited courage, leadership...
还愿意保护一个陌生人
...and willingness to protect a man you hardly knew.
- 颁个勋章给我好了  - 我宁可给你一份工作
- So give me a medal.  - I'd rather give you a job.
你看看我，我看来像是执法人员吗？
Look at me. Do I look like a fan of law enforcement?
今天是你的幸运日
This is your lucky day, Xander.
你有机会可以报答国家…
This is your chance to pay your Uncle Sam...
感谢它让你享受自由
...for all your wonderful freedoms.
工作本身并不难
The job's not that difficult.
我只是要你去见一些人，查明他们的底细
I want you to meet people and find out what you can about them.
那一种人？
What type of people?
危险、下流、野蛮，你们那种人
Dangerous, dirty, tattooed, uncivilized. Your kind of people.
等等
Hold up.
我这种人会说“去你的，大花脸”
My kind of people would say, "Kiss my ass, scarface."
此时我通常会拔枪相向，再礼貌的…
Usually I'd take my gun, press it to your temple...
请你照我的话去做
...and ask you very politely to do what I want.
但你并不怕死，这让我们陷入了窘境
But you're not afraid of death. That puts us in a quandary.
- 我想讨论就到此结束了  - 还没
- We better call this a day, then.  - Not just yet.
你看过动物园里的狮子吗？
You ever watch lions at the zoo?
透过它们的眼睛，你就能分辨哪只是野生的
You can tell which were captured in the wild by the look in their eyes.
大野猫
The wild cat.
它记得奔驰草原的快乐、猎杀的快感
She remembers running across the plain, the thrill of the hunt.
四百磅的猎杀高手，被关着
Four hundred pounds of killing fury locked in a box.
过一阵子，它们眼神变得呆滞…
But after a while, their eyes glaze over...
你看得出它的灵魂已死
...and you can tell their soul has died.
人也是一样
The same thing happens to a man.
联邦监狱可不是儿童乐园
Leavenworth Federal Penitentiary is no joke.
他们会把你这种狂人丢进单人牢房取乐
They'll take a wild man and throw him in solitary just for fun.
不再有山可爬，不再有浪可冲
No more mountains to board, no more oceans to surf.
只有一个小牢房，不见天日，只有一个粪桶
Just a 6-by-8 cell with no window and only a bucket to shit in.
但你只要帮个忙，就能免去一切
You can avoid that by doing me this favor.
你根本没有我的把柄
You don't have shit on me.
我注意到你的后颈有三个“X”的刺青
I noticed you have three X's tattooed on the back of your neck.
我觉得那满适合你的，因为你背负三项罪名
I think that's rather appropriate since you're looking at three strikes.
偷车、危害公安，还有你那个跳桥特技…
Grand theft, reckless endangerment, and that bridge stunt of yours...
让你彻底输了三次
...makes you a three-time loser.
也许你该自称为“XXX”
Maybe you ought to call yourself "Triple X."
但如果你照我的话去做，我就让你无罪开释
But if you do what I want, I'll make all your transgressions go away...
让你回去过你那可笑的生活
...and let you get back to that pathetic excuse of a life.
或者你认为我该跟你一样
Or you think maybe I should be like you.
被打个脸上开花
Get all shot up for the old Stars and Stripes.
你每回照镜子时一定很自傲
I bet that flag is a real comfort every time you look in the mirror.
这只是个我为国付出的小代价
A small price I paid for putting foot to ass for my country.
怎么样，XXX？
So, what's it going to be, Triple X?
你想立刻上路…
You want to get on a plane...
还是给我一句“去你的，大花脸”？
...or is "Kiss my ass, scarface" your final answer?
[布拉格，捷克]
你叫什么名字？
Yo. What's your name, slick?
我叫伊凡
My name is lvan.
- 伊凡？那你呢？ - 我叫伊凡
- lvan? What's your name, buddy?  - My name is lvan.
你们都叫伊凡？
You're both lvan?
坐下
Take a seat.
笨蛋，美国探员呢？
Idiots! Where is the American agent?
这就是了
This is him, Sir.
我们最好再订个装尸袋
We better order another bodybag.
有什么事吗？
Guys, what's up?
我叫你坐下
I told you to sit down.
我在飞机上坐半天了，我想站
I've just been on a plane for 12 hours. I think I'll stand.
我是苏米兰，捷克秘密警察
My name is Milan Sova, Czech secret police.
你到这里，就得受我管辖
Here, you are under my jurisdiction.
你听我的命令，照我的话去做
You take my orders, you do what I say.
如果你变得碍手碍脚，我就杀了你
If you become any kind of an inconvenience, I'll shoot you.
很好，我就住这？
That's great. Is this where I'm staying?
你会在此是因你的政府逼我们
Your government is putting pressure on mine.
这是一桩国内事务，你们这是干涉捷克内政
This is an internal Czech affair that you are interfering with.
我警告你，别在我家撒野
I will warn you once: Don't shit in my lawn.
取得你们政府想要的情报后，就快点滚
Get whatever information your government seeks and get out.
明人不说暗话
Let's get this straight.
你也许不想让我来，而我根本也不想来
You may not want me here, but I definitely don't want to be here.
再说，我没受任何人管辖过
Two, I've never been under anyone's jurisdiction.
第三，如果你想杀人…
Three, if you're going to shoot anybody...
去杀卖这套衣服给你的人吧
...shoot that monkey that sold you the suit.
我很累，我要睡了
Now, I'm tired. I'm going to sleep.
三小时后出发
Be ready in three hours.
俱乐部里的人有两个共通点：
Everybody in this club has two things in common:
- 他们都很有钱，也都是罪犯  - 我绝对合适，只是我并不有钱
- They're rich and they're criminals.  - I'll fit in, except for the rich part.
- 记住，我们互不相识  - 真希望是如此
- Remember, we don't know each other.  - I wish we didn't.
给我来杯红莓苏打
Yeah, can I get a cranberry club soda?
这放后面，我会给你小费
Throw this back there? I'll tip you something.
就放后面
Put it in the back.
这要多少？有存根吗？
How much? Do I get a ticket?
他们在那里，“无政府99”
That's them. Anarchy 99.
看见坐在中间沙发那个人了？
You see the guy on the couch?
那就是尤里，他是老大
That's Yorgi. He's the leader.
他拥有六间这样的俱乐部，全都是金鸡母
He owns this club and five others like it. All, how do you say, cash cows.
美国佬？！
American?!
我是美国人，我要见尤里，尤里？！
Guys, I'm American. I'm going to see Yorgi. Yorgi!
尤里，听说你就是
Hey, Yorgi! I hear you're the guy...
我听说可以找你买车
I heard you're the guy to talk to about cars.
请你出去
Take yourself outside.
出去？我才刚…
Take myself outside? I'm just...
好吧，我不受欢迎
Okay. I'm not welcome.
也许你宁愿条子进你的俱乐部
Guess you'd rather have cops in your club.
想谈谈吗？
Want to talk?
过来告诉我哪个是条子…
Hey, you silly boy. Come with me and show me the cop...
别弄错了
...and don't be mistake.
看到那个傢伙了？穿的很蠢的那个
See that guy there, with the suit made out of drapes?
那个就是条子
That's a cop.
怎么了？我才刚喝一杯
Is there a problem? I just had a drink, you know?
我付过钱了，我会给很大一笔小费的
I already paid. I'm going to give a big tip, you know?
这是干嘛？我什么都没做啊
So, what is this all about? I've done nothing.
什么都没做？你是做什么的？
You've done nothing? Who do you work for?
我在银行工作，怎么？
I work in a bank. So what?
少扯了…
You've got to be....
你干嘛？住手
What are you doing? Stop it! Stop it!
这是什么？学生证吗？
What's that, your bus pass?
捷克警察、捷克警察
Czech 5-0. Czech 5-0.
给我离开
Leave my club.
你怎么知道的？
How did you know?
我怎么知道？他付钱的时候，警徽反光差点害我瞎掉
When he was paying for his drinks, he was flashing his badge to half the bar.
条子跟蟑螂一样
Cops like plague.
不管收买多少，总还有人要钱
No matter how many you pay, there's always another with his hand out.
我也是混道上的，我暸解
I'm from the streets. I know cops, believe me.
我很感谢你引起我们注意，问题是为什么？
I appreciate you bringing this to our attention. My question to you is why?
我想没人喜欢条子混进来
I figure, no one likes cops crashing their party.
我想我帮你忙，就能说上话
I figure, I do you a solid, we could talk.
我想买车
I just want to buy cars, man.
这傢伙是不是想上我？
Is this guy going to hump my leg?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
桑德凯吉
Xander Cage.
我就知道
I knew it.
你玩滑雪板、机车样样都行
You are amazing on snowboard, motorbike, everything.
- 你真行  - 谢了
- You're awesome.  - Thank you, man.
我弟有点疯，他也很崇拜你
My brother is crazy too, and a great admirer of yours.
他看过很多你的带子，来谈吧
He has seen your tapes many times. Now we can talk business.
请这边来
This way, please.
约娜
Yelena.
欢迎进入桑德特区
Welcome to the Xander zone.
有趣，真有趣
Now, that's funny. That's funny.
坐，凯吉先生
Sit down, Mr. Cage.
我朋友都叫我X
My friends call me X.
X，你想要什么？
So, X, what exactly are you wanting?
法拉利，高级跑车，先买十辆
Ferraris, high-end pasta rockets, 10 to start.
这辆车，第十辆，在欧洲很难找
This car, number 10, will be very difficult to find in Europe.
那辆是我要的，我把它列进去是想从中获利
That one's for me. I put it in there to get something out of the deal.
你果然很懂车
Well, you certainly know your cars.
是啊，汽车、机车、滑板，我全都行
Yeah. Cars, bikes, boards. You name it.
我喜欢快速又能耍特技的东西
I like anything fast enough to do something stupid in.
是啊
Yes.
十辆车根本没利润可言，我们出价一百五十万美金
Ten cars is hardly worth the effort. A lousy 1 .5 million, U.S.
等一等
Now, hold on a second.
对我背后的美国金主而言，这十辆只是开胃小菜
The American buyers I represent, to them, 10 cars is an appetizer.
- 最多一百万，阿姐  - 一百四吧
- And it's a mil max, sister.  - How about a million four?
我想最多一百二
I was thinking more like a mil two.
你知道什么是电汇吗？
Do you know what a wire transfer is?
她不是来闹场的吧？
Is she for real?
阿姐，你没别的事好做了吗？
Sweetheart, is there anything you need to do?
男人谈生意女人少插嘴
Let us big boys have a conversation.
谈生意是要用大脑的
"Conversation," a word with four syllables.
你要不要先去装个脑袋？
Do you want some ice before your brain overheats?
是啊，你也先去装颗心吧，如果你找得到心的话
Ice. Yeah, you could chisel some off your heart, if you could find it.
一切会尽快进行，只要你给我帐号
This would work a lot faster, princess, if I had an account number.
你有四十八小时的时间汇款
You have 48 hours to complete the transfer.
- 别浪费我的时间  - 喔，我哪敢
- Don't waste my time.  - I wouldn't dream of it.
事实上，我会多汇几块送你上礼仪学校
I might throw in a couple extra bucks and send you to charm school.
生意谈完，来狂欢吧
Now that business is finished, we party.
辣妹们，进来吧
Bitches, come!
喂？
Yeah?
靠，我以为这只是手机
Shit, I thought this was a cell phone.
睡的甜吧？
Have a nice rest?
小声点，我一小时前才睡
Dial it down. I got to sleep an hour ago.
我们给你一份特别准备的清单，谁教你变更的？
You were given a specific list of cars. Who told you to alter it?
清单上的车很烂，他们会看穿
The cars sucked. They would've seen through it.
你们真该换旅行社
You guys should switch travel agents.
我已经弄到你要的情报了
I got that info you wanted.
等一等
Hang on a second.
准备好了？
You guys ready for this?
姓名、生日、红军军阶
Names, birthdays, ranks in the Red Army.
爱吃的东西？你怎么弄到的？
Favorite foods? How did you get this?
柯亚，尤里的小弟，他刚好是极限运动的爱好者
Kolya, Yorgi's younger brother, happens to be an action sports fanatic.
所以他很崇拜我
So naturally, he's a fan.
等他猛灌三瓶伏特加之后，他就无话不说了
But when you kill a bottle of vodka in three swigs, you'll talk.
- 我还有东西要给你  - 什么？
- I got something else.  - What?
他们的个人银行帐号，我放到哪里去了？
Their personal bank account number. Where did I put that?
偷车、夜总会、应召站、勒索
Stolen cars, nightclubs, prostitution, extortion.
这些人有什么特别的？这种人我们美国多的是
What's the big deal? We got criminals like this in the U.S.
你负责搜集情报，不是问问题
Your job isn't to ask questions.
我功成身退，谢谢，我要回家了
Well, I did my job, thank you. I'm coming home.
还没
Not just yet.
你的称职害了你自己，我要你接近这些人
You're a victim of your own success. Get closer to these guys.
- 这些人是酷，但还不够酷  - 更深入一点
- They're cool, but not that cool.  - Go deeper.
我会派人带些道具去帮你
I'll send a guy with a care package to help you.
- 我以为我们谈好的  - 你变更车子，我变更交易
- I thought we had a deal.  - You change cars, I change the deal.
帮我这个忙，你就能回家
Do this for me, you can come home.
你要派人拯救世界，也要确定那人喜欢这世界
If you send someone to save the world, make sure they like it the way it is.
我的胸肌很壮，我推举都举两百二十五磅
I have a really firm chest. I bench, like, 225.
推举，在举重室
Like, bench. Weight room. Bye.
- 就是他  - 等等，你就是XXX？
- That's him.  - Wait. You're Triple X?
- 你就是送道具的？ - 对，李托比探员
- You're the care package?  - Agent Toby Lee Shavers.
来吧
Come on.
纪本会送货来，你一定很重要
You have to rate high to get Gibbons to send this stuff.
我真希望能跟你一起行动，实地打击罪犯
I kind of wish I was going with you, mixed up in the fury of the situation.
这真够猛的，杀人、毁灭、搞破坏
Crazy. License to kill, death, destruction, mayhem.
枕头底下放枪，超级大坏蛋随时都可能跳出来
Got a gun under your pillow. Never know when some freak villain will pop out.
- 你当探员多久了？ - 两天
- How long you been with the agency?  - Two days.
靠，不会吧
You're shitting me. No way.
真差劲
That sucks.
是很差劲，但比坐牢好多了
Yeah, it sucks, but it beats jail.
差劲的是，我耗了六年时间
It sucks because I spent six years...
待在暗无天日的道具室里
...in the basement of some windowless, NSA, gadget freak room, man.
我有学位，我是麻省理工的
And I got a degree. I got a degree from MIT.
我是第一名毕业的
Phi Beta Kappa, magna cum laude.
而他们挑中你的原因
And they probably picked you up, what,
是你在牢里很会扛砖头？
pumping iron in San Quentin?
你有没有因为多话被扁过？
You ever get punched in the face for talking too much?
把东西拿给我看
Show me the stuff.
这是我的精心杰作，完美的典范
This one made my career, the definition of perfection:
多目标多功能连发手枪
My multi-purpose, multi-function field revolver.
- 我喜欢  - 那你会爱死这些
- Oh, I like this.  - Then you'll love these.
这些是附属子弹，什么都有，看见绿色的了？
These are all attachment darts. See the green ones?
麻醉子弹
Datura knockout darts.
碰！中弹者会倒下十二小时，醒来后不知身在何处…
Guy goes down for 12 hours, wakes up, doesn't know who he is...
他会头痛欲裂
...and his head's splitting like a cord of firewood.
我被那种子弹打中两次
I was shot twice by those.
还有红色的，这是镇静喷血弹
And the red ones are tranquilizer and blood-splatter darts.
中弹后的假死样子很逼真，跟死了一样
Looks like a kill shot without the aftereffects. Like death.
还有爆破弹、无线电追踪弹…
You've got exploding and surveillance darts...
还有标准的点四四子弹，如果你想开杀戒的话
...and your standard .44-caliber bullets, if you want to get nasty.
喷洒点鲜血，你懂我在说什么吧？
A little wet work. You know what I'm talking about, right?
你一定抢过便利商店吧？
Knocked over a few 7-Elevens, have we?
没，到是腿上上过石膏，我只能在家玩射击电玩
No, I had my leg in a cast for three months. All I did was play video games.
真是个悲伤的故事
That's a really sad story.
好吧，看看我的宝贝
Check this out, on to my baby.
鹰眼，有九种视觉强化模式
Eagle Eyes. Nine enhanced-vision modes.
每个小男孩的梦想，透视模式
Every little boy's dream: the penetrator mode.
看看吧
Check it out.
乖乖
Oh, my God.
- 她在看你  - 这个我要了
- She's checking you out, man.  - I'll hang on to these.
接着，我最新的发明
Now, on to my latest achievement.
我上周才完成的
I just put the finishing touches on them last week.
怎样？
What do you think?
- 绷带  - 不，你看着
- Bandages?  - No, Mr. X, watch and learn.
上面的火药足以炸穿墙壁…
There's enough primer to blow a hole in a vault...
炸死人，或任何你想炸的东西
...vaporize a human, or whatever agents like you might find a use for.
你看看
And check this out.
这是引爆器，够酷吧？
The detonator. How cool is that?
- 你最好退后一点  - 那只是绷带罢了
- You might want to back up for this.  - lt's a bandage.
躲到墙后
Just get behind the wall.
准备好了？
You ready?
我一直想说这句话
I've always wanted to say this.
引爆
Fire in the hole.
子弹已经上膛
It's loaded.
- 怎样？ - 太棒了
- So, what do you think?  - Beautiful.
你喜欢这些车？
You like the cars?
我喜欢，真棒
I love the cars, they're dope.
- 你喜欢那笔钱吧？ - 我喜欢，但我还没拿到
- You like the money?  - I love money, but I do not have it.
你看来混的不错，这些手下、名车
You look like you're doing very well. All these employees, beautiful cars.
我没时间跟你胡扯
This is no time for being funny.
[帐户余额 120万]
[款项收讫]
- 你不会以为我会赖帐吧？ - 我想都没想过
- You didn't think I wasn't good for it?  - lt never crossed my mind.
港口有艘货轮在等着，这是地址
A cargo ship's waiting for you in Rijeka. Here's the address.
这里真棒
This place is dope.
这辆是我的？
This one's mine?
第十辆
Car number 10.
柯亚在柏林找到的，它很难找
Kolya found it hiding in Berlin. It was very difficult to find.
不，拜托
No! Please.
让我来，你很慷慨的付了钱
Allow me. You were kind enough to give me the money.
请你…
Now, please...
开车吧
...drive.
不，让我来
No, allow me.
- 你挺正点的，尤里  - 有伏特加一切好办
- You're all right, Yorgi.  - Everything's all right with vodka.
请你今晚务必来参加派对，就在我的俱乐部里
You must come to party tonight. Big party at one of my clubs.
- 是吗？ - 没错
- Yeah?  - Yes.
怎么回事？
What's going on, my friend?
我不知道，你说呢，你上面是不是有埋伏人？
You tell me. You got a sniper up there or what?
他不是我们的人，是跟你来的
He's not with us, he must be with you.
胡扯，叫你的人下来
Bullshit! Tell your men to get down...
不然我就在你身上多开一个洞，听清楚了？
...or I'll give you another hole to breathe out of. Are we clear?
好吧，他不是你的人
All right. It's not yours.
我们一起去逮他吧
Let's go and get him together.
妈的，是之前闯俱乐部的条子
Son of a bitch. That same cop from the club.
烂条子
Filthy cop.
很多人会放狠话，但能冷静行动的人不多
Most people talk a lot. Few are up for the moment.
欢迎你加入“无政府99”
Welcome to Anarchy 99.
你干嘛这么对待自己？香烟迟早会要了你的命
Why do you do that to yourself? That cigarette will kill you one day.
我喜欢烟雾胜于空气，可以的话，我连睡觉都想吸烟
I like smoke better than air. If I could, I'd smoke in my sleep.
就算它害死我，我死后还想抽
I would still do it after it kills me.
你之前提到无政府
You were talking about Anarchy 99.
那是什么？你的机车俱乐部？
What is that, some motorcycle gang of yours?
是我们九九年离开祖国红军后所过的日子
It's what we've been living since 1999 when we left the army of Mother Russia.
我们有许多同志死于战争，我们受够这一切了
Many of our comrades died in combat, and we said, "To hell with this shit."
他们为何而死？政治？
They die for what? Politics?
谁的政治？不是我们的
Whose politics? Not ours!
所以我们当下决定，从此要为所欲为
So we decide from then on to do what we want, when we want.
为纪念他们，我们自称“无政府99”
It is in their honor we call ourselves Anarchy 99.
有首老庞克歌曲，歌词说：
You know, there's an old punk song. It says:
美国代表自由
The United States on behalf of freedom
但你若自以为自由
But if you think you're free
去趟小吃店，在小菜上撒泡尿
Go to the snack bar, Piss on the side dishes
- 你知道！ - 汪达合唱团的“无政府汉堡”
- You got it!  - "Anarchy Burger" by the Vandals.
我赞成你，但你要怎么做？
I'm with you, but what are you going to do?
到处都有法规、都有政府，以前有，以后也会一直有
You got rules and government everywhere. Always was, always will be.
也许不会一直有
Maybe not always.
别让他寂寞
Make sure he doesn't get lonely.
放开一点
Don't be shy.
想跳舞吗？
You want to dance?
喂，喂！
Hey. Hey!
喂！我舞技很棒的
Hey! I'm really a good dancer.
来两杯
Make that two.
好吧，你打算一直这样对我？
All right, it's going to be like that?
你气他，也别拿我出气啊
If you're mad at him, don't take it out on me.
我一直在想你们俩的关系
I've been trying to figure out the deal between you two all night.
你是他的女人？
You his woman or what?
对，我是，若付我一样多钱，我也能跟你
Yeah, I'm his woman. If you pay me as much, I'll be your woman too.
- 你喜欢吗？ - 喜欢
- Did you enjoy that?  - Yeah.
很好，因为它不会再发生了
Good, because it will never happen again.
原来的堡主有一天决定落跑
The original owners just one day decide to move out.
- 这里真棒  - 请不要拘礼
- This is amazing, man.  - Make yourself at home.
我帮你拿外套
Let me get your coat.
那小子怎么了？他喜欢外套？
What's up with your boy? He got a coat fetish?
不
Oh, no.
他爱上她了，笨蛋
He's in love with her. Dirty fool.
该上床了，天快亮了，约娜！
Time for bed, X. It's getting early. Yelena!
你带他去他的房间吧
Would you kindly show him his room?
- 你先请  - 不，你先
- After you.  - No, after you.
- 不，你先  - 不，我坚持
- No, after you.  - No, I insist.
这里就是了
That's it.
跟我上床的最后一次机会
Last chance to tuck me in.
祝你好梦
Good morning.
我要为国奋战一番
The things I'm going to do for my country.
这不关我的事，但是用电钻…
It's none of my business, but a power drill and some titanium bits...
会比用相机有用多了
...will get you a lot further than that camera.
你不该在这里的
You're not supposed to be in here.
我本来是想去上厕所
I was on my way to the bathroom.
你的藉口呢？
What's your excuse?
我不需要藉口
I don't need an excuse.
你真行
Oh, you're good.
但还不够行
But not that good.
我是来拍摄尤里的保险箱
I came in here to photograph Yorgi's safe.
因为我觉得它可能很值钱
I thought it might be worth a lot to somebody.
拜托，你冷血、聪明又危险
Come on. You're cold, intelligent and vicious.
你的眼神泄露了你的身分
It's your eyes that give you away.
就在我射杀那条子的时候
They gave you away when I shot that cop.
你现在打算怎么做？
What are you going to do now?
我现在要请你吃午餐
Now I'm going to take you to lunch.
还有，我杀的那个条子，他没死
Oh, and that cop I shot, isn't dead.
我有情报要给你
I have some information for you.
我一直都用得上情报，你是谁？你怎会有我的号码？
I can always use information. Who is this? How did you get this number?
关于桑德凯吉的重要情报
Yes. Important information that you need about Xander Cage.
- 你不喜欢外国人？ - 没错，你是一只猪
- So you don't like foreigners, do you?  - No, you're a pig.
你的相好呢？他也是猪？
Is your boyfriend a pig too?
你应该认得你的同类啊
You should recognize one of your kind.
告诉我条子的事
Now, tell me about the cop.
若我说我跟你想像的不一样，你会怎么说？
What if I told you I'm not who you think I am?
我可以帮你解决你的问题
That I could get you out of the mess you're in?
是吗？我有什么问题？
Really? And what mess am I in?
它让你趁大家熟睡时，蹑手蹑脚刺探情报
The mess that makes you sneak around the castle when everyone's asleep.
条子的事呢？
The cop?
你看这个，这叫镇静喷血弹
See this? It's called a blood-splatter dart.
撞击很真实，但却无害，主要是红色颜料
The impact's real, but it's harmless. Red paint, mostly.
为什么？
Why?
我是个情报员
I'm a secret agent.
你这不是在糗我吗？
Are you sure you don't want to embarrass me?
- 拜托  - 有这么好笑吗？
- Come on.  - What's so funny about that?
你看看你
I mean, look at you.
我隶属于美国国安局
I work for the NSA.
你真会搞笑
You're funny, you know that?
约娜，我是阿奇
Yelena, it's Kirill.
尤里发现凯吉是美国情报员
Yorgi found out that Cage is an American agent.
你知道我在说什么吗？你有危险，亲爱的
Do you understand what I'm telling you? You are in danger, my love.
对街的大楼，雕像后面
The building across the street. The statue.
带他出来，其他的由我来
Bring him outside. I will do the rest.
是谁？你的相好？
What was that, your boyfriend?
假设你说的是真的
Let's say you are who you say you are.
- 你能帮我做些什么？ - 你想要什么？
- What can you do for me?  - What do you want?
我要免诉权，美国给我庇护和公民身分
I want immunity from prosecution, asylum in the U.S. and citizenship.
住迈阿密，外加有钱男友一个？
How about a condo on South Beach and a rich boyfriend?
那些我自己来就行
Those I can get for myself.
- 你要我怎么做？ - 我要知道“无政府99”的详情
- What do you want?  - I need to know more about Anarchy 99.
你想知道详情？
You want to know about Anarchy 99?
你看到辣妹、俱乐部和派对了
You've seen the girls, the clubs, the parties.
但你看不到白天发生的事
What you don't see is what goes on during the day.
去年活动很频繁，人们进进出出的
There's been a lot of activity in the last year. People coming in and out.
- 俄罗斯科学家  - 他们在干嘛？
- Russian scientists.  - Well, what are they up to?
不知，他们在地下室，我不能去
They go in the basement and I'm not allowed in.
现在是你设法进去的好时机
Now's a good time for you to get invited.
尤里知道你是情报员，阿奇正在外面拿枪指着你
Yorgi knows you're an agent. Kirill is waiting with his rifle.
- 哪里…？ - 别看！
- Where...?  - Don't look!
这里有后门
There's a back door.
走后门，他们就知道你警告我
They'll know you warned me.
走前门，他就会射杀你
If you go out the front, he'll put a bullet in your eye.
- 你有带枪吗？ - 一直都有
- You still packing?  - Always.
准备用枪吧
Get ready to use it.
- 你有何计划？ - 他还爱着你，对吧？
- What's your plan?  - He's still in love with you.
- 除非有把握，他不会开枪  - 这就是你的计划？你还真行
- He'll wait for a clear shot.  - That's your plan? Thank you. Great.
拔枪
Draw!
他上路了
He's on the way.
纪本，我最喜爱的绑匪头头，下回派辆礼车来接我吧
Gibbons! My favorite kidnapper. Next time send a limo.
哇咧，你别闹了吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
你已打败我了，不用再折磨我
You already broke me. No need to get cruel and unusual.
机票？这可好玩了
A ticket? Now, that's funny.
- 我现在要去哪？ - 回家
- Where am I going to go now?  - Home.
回家？
Home?
你的身分已被揭穿，你没用了
Your cover's blown. You're not useful.
就这样？没我的事了？
That's it? I'm done?
没错，我们情报已足供进行下一步行动
No tricks. We have enough intel to move forward.
- 谁去行动？ - 扫荡小组，快又有效
- With what?  - Sweeper team: quick, clean, effective.
不用担心，事情很快就会解决
Don't worry about it. It'll all be over soon.
你派扫荡小组去杀光所有人？
You mean a sweeper team to come in and kill everybody?
他们并非全都是大坏蛋
Not all of them are as bad as you think.
你得杀警才能混进去，他们这还不算是坏人？
You had to shoot a cop. How "not as bad as I think" could they be?
好吧，听着
Okay, look.
事情有点复杂，里面有个女人，约娜
We've got a complication. There's a girl. Yelena.
永远都是有个女人
There's always a girl.
她想逃出来，而我派她回去帮你搜集情报
She wants out and I sent her back in to get more intel for you.
没时间玩游戏，决定已经下了
There's no time to play favorites. The cards have been dealt.
什么叫决定已经下了？
What do you mean the cards have been dealt?
你根本不认识她
You don't even know her, man.
对了，你给我们的银行帐号
Oh, by the way, that bank number you gave us?
你朋友和约娜，转帐大笔的现金…
Your friends and Yelena have made some large cash transfers...
给一群俄罗斯科学家，他们专精于…
...to a group of Russian scientists known to specialize and traffic...
生化武器
...in biological weapons.
- 老大，她跟那没关系  - 回家吧
- She had nothing to do with it.  - Go home.
- 她…  - 这是命令
- She ain't...!  - That's an order.
情况如何？
How's it going?
人生真烂！
Life is shit!
是啊，但你又能如何？
Yeah, well what can you do?
过了这扇门，你就要效忠到底
Through this door, you are with us to the end.
- 你确定要这样？ - 我确定
- Are you sure that's what you want?  - I'm sure.
这是亚哈号，它就像是艘太阳能潜水艇
This is Ahab. Think of it as solar-powered submarine.
它能绕行全球，命中目标
It can circumnavigate the globe to reach its target.
它只需要在水面上搜集阳光，就能完成任务
It need only surface to gather sunshine and to do its business.
什么任务？
What is it? What's its business?
送礼物给乖小孩
Dropping off presents to all the good little boys and girls.
我们明天就可以完成
My team will be finished tomorrow.
你们呢？
How about you?
我们好了
We're finished now.
尼可莱！
Nikolai!
准备火箭
Bring the rockets.
[亚哈号]
给你设定
The detonator is for you.
毒气开始混合…
Yorgi! The binary agents are mixing...
会害死大家！
...it will kill us all!
看起来真像小白鼠
Looks like little white mouse.
拜拜，小白鼠
Bye-bye, little mouse.
天啊
My God.
他们的工作已经完成，现在他们成了累赘
They did their job and now they were liability.
我们不需要太多知情的人
We don't need anyone talking about our business.
风扇会抽出毒气，让它通过水
The gas gets sucked through the extractor fans, passed into water...
再转化为完全无毒的空气
...and broken down to become, once again, completely harmless.
真安静
So quiet.
难怪它会被称为“寂静之夜”
I know now why they call it Silent Night.
去吃点东西
Let's get some food.
快去查是怎么回事
Find out what's going on!
搞什么？
What the hell was that?
这招管用
That works.
引爆
Fire in the hole.
你怎么会在这里？
Sova. What are you doing here, man?
你先是在酒吧里陷害我，接着又开枪杀我
First you set me up in the bar. Then you shoot me in the back.
我老板这么对我，我再这么对你，这是恶性循环
My boss does it to me. I did it to you. It's a vicious circle.
- 你觉得这很有趣？ - 不，我不觉得
- You think it's funny?  - No.
你不会是怀恨在心吧？
You didn't take it personally, did you?
我设法混进去，我们是站同一边的，记得吧？
I did what I had to do to get in. We're on the same side.
抱歉，我换边了
I'm sorry. I switched sides.
你对我太过份了，我的政府给的也没尤里多
You pushed me too far. My government doesn't pay as well as Yorgi.
我的政府给的是尤里给的两倍…
My government pays twice as much...
你以为这样突然跳进来这行…
Think you could just walk into the spy business...
- 就能一切顺风如意？ - 那你要怎样？射杀我？
- ...and have all the angles figured out?  - What are you going to do, shoot me?
你希望我射哪里？头？
Where? In the head, to be quick?
还是胸，好让我看看你的心脏
Or in the chest for an open casket, so I can see your heart?
我想一下
Can I think about it?
你这是干嘛？
What are you doing?!
我听到你讲话，知道你在哪里
I heard you talking. I could tell where you were in the room.
你怎么会跟伊凡在一起？
What are you doing with the lvans?
怎么回事？
What's going on?
我有些话之前没对你说
There's something I didn't have the time to tell you.
我也是个情报员
I'm an agent as well.
我是俄罗斯情报局的探员
I'm an agent for FSB, Russian Intelligence.
很像你们的中情局
You know, like your CIA.
- 我卧底两年了  - 两年？
- I've been undercover for two years.  - Two years?
你的计划是什么？等他们老死吗？
What was your plan, let them die of old age?
我们根本没有计划
There was no plan.
一年半以前，局里改组，我不再收到指令
A year ago, Intelligence gets reorganized, I stop getting orders.
他们把我给忘了，我只能尽力求生，你懂吗？
They forget about me. And I did what I must to survive. You understand?
我懂个屁，我才入行一周而已
What do I understand? I've been an agent for a week.
但我老板得知道一切详情
But my boss needs to know what we know now.
- 好吗？ - 好
- Okay?  - Okay.
潜艇会施放神经毒气“寂静之夜”
The submarine's purpose is to deploy a nerve agent called Silent Night.
它的配方在苏联解体后就失踪
It's been missing since the Soviet Union's collapse in '91 .
它能屠杀百万人口
It can kill millions.
我们早知他们有鬼，你查到了
We knew they were up to something. You found out.
- 干的好，XXX  - 原来根本没什么扫荡小组
- That's excellent work, Triple X.  - There was never a sweeper team.
我若叫你别去跳帝国大厦…
If I said don't jump off the Empire State Building....
- 没错，我铁定会去跳  - 我激励了你
- You're right. I'd definitely do it.  - I inspired you.
看吧，我是掌权者，我理当这么做
I'm an authority figure, that's what I'm supposed to do.
听着，我的人已经接手
Look, my men are on this now.
- 你该回家了  - 那约娜呢？
- It's time for you to come home.  - What about Yelena?
我无权给她庇护
I'm not authorized to give her asylum.
但我保证你回来时一定搞定
But I promise it'll be done by the time you get here.
回来吧，桑德，这是命令
Come home, Xander. That's an order.
尤里多快就能发射这玩意？
How soon can Yorgi launch this thing?
他们叫你回去，你们的人接手…
You were told to go home! Your people are handling...
多快？
How soon, Yelena?
很快，但这不关我们的事了
Soon. But it's not our problem anymore!
他们若提前行动，就事关重大
If they get ahead of schedule, it's everyone's.
不可能的，他有军队、碉堡，你根本没有机会
He's got an army, a fortress. You don't stand a chance!
我曾为很多蠢事冒险，这是第一件对我有意义的事
I've risked my life for stupid reasons. This is the first one that makes sense.
这不是特技表演，你会送命的
This is not one of your stunts. You'll die in this, you know that.
我知道你若没回去…
If you don't go back in there...
他就会知道出事了
...he'll know something's wrong.
你不能要我回去，不行
You can't ask me to go back there. You can't.
知道最讽刺的是什么吗？我是自愿争取这任务的
You want to know something ironic? I volunteered for this assignment.
我想有所贡献
I wanted to make a difference.
我努力争取这任务
I fought for it.
那就完成它
Then finish it.
记得你吻我之后，我说了什么？
Remember what I told you, after you kissed me?
- 没有下次？ - 我说谎
- Never again?  - I lied.
你仔细分析，其实我很单纯
But when you break it down, I'm a simple man.
我很高兴能跟捷克美女…
I'd be happy with a beautiful Czech girl...
怪胎！纪本下了新指令，上车
Hey, geek! Got new orders from Gibbons. Get in.
- 我要那些全装进这车里  - 没问题
- I want all that in here.  - Done.
城堡到处装满监视器
The castle's covered with surveillance cameras.
所以我们才无法靠近
That's why we cannot get close enough.
等等，所以我要去摧毁山脚下的…
Hang on. That's why I need to knock out the communications tower...
联络塔
...at the base of the mountain.
这里有人会开飞机吗？
Is there anyone here who knows how to fly a plane?
我会
I can.
这些山峰附近乱流太多
Too much turbulence around these mountains!
把我送到那个塔上方就好
Just get me in line with that tower!
剩下的交给我
I'll do the rest!
跳吧
Go now!
维多，有访客来了！
Viktor! We got company!
活逮他，再好好折磨他！
Catch him fast. Kill him slow!
新鲜的雪花真棒
Nothing like fresh powder.
老相好，你是不是头昏了？
Yelena, my sweet dove, did you get confused?
你的任务是那条子杀了桑德后，再杀了他
Your assignment was to kill the cop after he killed X.
这样不是个好俄罗斯卧底密探
Not good for undercover agent from Russian Intelligence.
我一直都知道你的底细…
I knew about you all along...
能随意摆布并利用你，真是好玩
...and it was my pleasure to twist you and use you how I saw fit.
还有你
And you.
在众人之中，我以为你会懂…
Of all people, I thought you'd understand...
我想达成的梦想
...what I'm trying to accomplish.
你想像一下？
Can you imagine?
想像布拉格在毒气云团下…
Imagine a city like Prague vanishing...
被消灭殆尽
...in a cloud of poison gas.
还有汉堡、伦敦、华盛顿
Then Hamburg, London, Washington.
凶手不明，原因也不明，所以大家兵戎相见
Imagine not knowing who did it, or why. And so they turn on each other.
这些人攻击那些人，那些人侵略这些人
These guys attack those guys. Those guys invade these guys.
很快地，全世界闹内讧
Soon, whole world implodes.
政府全都消失
Imagine governments disappearing.
最后…
And in the end...
达成一个绝对完美的自由状态
...imagine facing absolute, beautiful freedom.
但你们都无缘亲眼目睹了
But neither of you will be there to see it.
跟维多一样
Like Viktor.
还有柯亚
Like Kolya.
掩护我
Cover me!
帮我解开
Get me out of this thing!
他拿走硬碟，他要发射亚哈号
He took the hard drive. He's going to launch Ahab!
自己选
Pick one.
伊凡，轰了那些狙击手！
Ivan, take out that nest!
你要扳开保险才行
You have to turn the safety off.
尽量拖住他们
Hold them off as long as you can.
再见了，朋友
See you, my friend.
快啊
Come on, baby.
停！他困住我们了
Stop! He's got us pinned down.
该死
Shit.
你有火箭筒啊
You got a bazooka!
别把自己当警察，当电玩高手，随便开轰啊
Stop thinking Prague police and start thinking PlayStation. Blow shit up!
这不是火箭筒，这是热感火箭
This is not bazooka. This is heat-seeker rocket.
感热？
Heat-seeker?
架好它
Set it.
那痞子在抽烟
The son of a bitch is smoking.
我说过他会被烟害死，走吧
I told him that cigarette would kill him.
学学怎么开枪吧，笨蛋
Learn how to shoot, piece of shit!
快，帮我把他拉出来
Quick! Help me pull him out!
那玩意半小时内会抵达市内
It will hit the city in 30 minutes!
各位，我需要直升机
Guys. I need a helicopter.
我需要交通工具，我需要…
I need transportation. I need a...
你在这，我在找你，一切搞定
X, there you are. I gave you everything you wanted.
这玩意只差不会飞了
This thing will damn near fly now.
你耍我，纪本根本没下令
You screwed me. Gibbons didn't authorize this.
他会整死我们，我会完蛋
He'll hang us both out to dry.
- 托比探员  - 什么事？
- Agent Shavers.  - Yeah?
我要升你的职
I'm going to give you a field promotion.
接手这个现场，由你全权负责
Take over, finish the mop-up. You're in charge.
遵命，我保证达成任务，我决不会令你失望
Yes, sir! I'm the man for the job! I won't let you down!
等等、等等
Wait! Wait! Wait!
操作手册，你会需要的
Almost forgot the manual. You'll need this.
老大，去拯救世界吧
Hey, X. Go kick some ass.
那玩意时速肯定有八十哩，我们要怎么停下它？
That thing must be going 80 mph! How do we stop it?!
没办法，控制中心在上面的透明圆顶里
We can't! The controls are on the bubble panel.
- 看到了？ - 看到了
- You see it?  - Yeah.
硬碟就在里面
The hard drive's in there!
你有操作手册，查一查有什么可用的机关
You got the manual. See if Shavers put in anything we could use.
- 他的字迹很潦草  - 快点
- He's got very bad handwriting.  - Come on!
火焰喷射器、迷你炸弹、车轮盖炸弹、火箭发射器
Flame throwers, mini-bombs, exploding hubcaps, rocket launchers!
这是辆坦克，你不能拿它对付亚哈号
This is a tank. You can't use any of it on Ahab.
寂静之夜要在深水中引爆才行
Silent Night only breaks down in deep water.
- 我要上去  - 什么？
- I'll have to get on it!  - What?
我要上去
I'll have to get on it.
亚哈号再二十二分就到达布拉格了
Our surveillance puts Ahab 22 minutes outside of Prague.
- 我们该疏散整个城市  - 二十二分钟疏散一百五十万人？
- We should evacuate the city.  - 22 minutes for 1.5 million people?
找空军支援，我们可能得在水面上炸了它
Call air support. We may need to blow it out of the water.
- 要是我们击中它…  - 那整个城市就完了
- lf we hit that thing...  - This city will die.
危机必须受到控制
And the crisis will be contained!
牺牲一个城市总胜过十个
One city's better than 10.
还有一件事，有辆跑车跟亚哈号并行前进
Another thing: A blue GTO is traveling parallel to Ahab.
该死，这条路会回到河边吗？
Shit! Does this road go back to the river?
快点，查导航地图啊
Come on! Check the GPS!
会！在十五哩后的狄维镇！
Yes, it does! Fifteen miles at the town of Davle!
这里一定有我们能用的东西
There's got to be something here we could use.
鱼叉炮、降落伞座椅、可弹射车顶
Harpoon gun, parachutes built into seats, ejectable roof.
全都没用
It's all useless!
还有多远？
How far are we?
那河就在下个村落后面
The river is just beyond the next village.
我要直接冲过去，发射火箭
I'm going through! Use the rocket launcher!
- 二十二号！ - 快按
- Twenty-two!  - Hit it!
那是火焰发射器，用火箭
That was a flamethrower! Use the rockets!
是三十二号，我说过了，我说过他字迹很潦草
It's 32! I told you! I told you he had bad handwriting!
快按
Hit it!
托比全都装上来了，查手册，我们一定漏了什么
Shavers loaded this thing. We're missing something.
后面有更多武器，你看
There are more weapons here on the back. Look.
- 你来开车！ - 什么？你疯了
- Take the wheel!  - What? You're crazy!
刹车！刹车！
The brake! The brake!
加油！加油！
The gas! The gas!
你在干嘛？
X, what are you doing?
五分钟后抵达目标上空
Five minutes to target.
说话啊，你在干嘛？
X, talk to me! What are you doing?
- 你说过有个可弹射车顶  - 对，就是那里
- You said there was an ejectable roof.  - Right here!
按下去！
Hit it!
该死，太远了
Shit! It's out of range!
- 那里有座桥，过桥去！ - 好
- There's a bridge! Cross the bridge!  - Okay.
加油
Come on.
Come on!
- 中了！ - 好耶！
- Got you!  - Yes!
- 我真希望有带摄影机！ - 你说什么？
- I wish I had a camera!  - What you talking about?
因为这次的特技肯定炫毙了
This is gonna be one hell of a trick.
三分钟后抵达
Three minutes to target.
一分钟后抵达
One minute to target.
快、快
Move! Move! Move!
快让开、让开
Out of the way!
望远镜
Eyes!
十秒后抵达
Ten seconds to target.
目标在望
Target in sight.
取消空中行动，叫战机撤退
Call the jets off. Tell the jets to stand down!
欢迎进入桑德特区
Welcome to the Xander zone!
零污染，我明白，长官，零污染
Zero contamination level. I understand, sir. Zero contamination level.
你就是约娜？
You Yelena?
纪本先生
Mr. Gibbons.
我答应桑德要让你去美国
I promised Xander you could go to America.
我言出必行
I'm a man of my word.
现在这也没什么意义了
It doesn't make much difference now, does it?
他还活着，快过来
He's alive! He's alive! Come here!
快把他弄回来，快，快去
Get him out of there, double-time. Go! Move!
- 布拉布拉！ - 什么？我听不见！
- Bora Bora!  - What? I can't hear you!
布拉布拉
Bora Bora.
你晒伤了
You're getting burnt.
桑德，你在吗？
Xander, you there?
我知道你在，我能透过卫星看到你
I know you're there, Xander. I've got you here on satellite magnification.
回电给我，我有要事相谈
Call me. We got a whole new thing to talk about.
出大事来着
Something very important has come up.
对了…
Oh, by the way...
你已通过了纪氏测验
...you passed the test. The Gibbons test.
你别闹了
You gotta be kidding me.
导演 罗布·科恩
编剧 里奇·威尔克斯
制片 尼尔·H·莫瑞兹
执行制片
尼尔·H·莫瑞兹
托德·加纳
执行制片
范·迪塞尔
乔治·扎克
摄影指导
迪恩·塞姆勒
艺术指导
加文·巴奎特
剪辑
克里斯·莱本森
保罗·拉贝尔
乔尔·内古龙
作曲与指挥
兰迪·艾德尔曼
音乐监制 凯西·尼尔森
视觉特效 乔尔·希内克
服装设计
萨尼娅·米科维奇·海斯
共同制片
克赖顿·贝林格
德里克·多希
选角导演
罗娜·克莱斯
凯特·多德
主演 范·迪塞尔
主演 艾莎·阿基多
主演 马尔顿·索克斯
主演 塞缪尔·杰克逊 … 纪本斯
丹尼·特乔
迈克尔·路夫
汤姆·艾弗瑞特
尼尔·H·莫瑞兹 摄制
罗伯·科恩 作品
革命电影工作室 出品
极限特工
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
纪念及呈献给
哈利·L·欧康诺
空中特技指导 还有亲爱的朋友